all right dead a machete me Martin
gimmick opinions and our membership is
indeed a coma tumor so you can explain
to the person about all the cool things
the Gouda okay go glam shocked open on
Long Beach alexk1018 Jim Reina but
really you have to split Dharma into two
kinds somebody tell me what they are
yeah the books and the ideas okay the
books and the ideas you know in this
book Dharma yeah it's done okay and it
will it can protect you it's okay but
the idea that the understanding the two
husbands that's real protection okay
whether you use it or not I don't know
but it can protect you if you use it
okay but you have to use it okay so dope
here it says stupid on ligature you have
to use both really write this expression
top and long is so popular in Buddhism
that some monks name is long talk you
know okay
can a junction Jelena chill our data
giving and then younger son so that
brings us to this meditation number four
can you show the photo yeah
when you get to when you're in your
three-day retreat you'll be doing a
meditation on this picture okay
and it's supposed to show both kinds of
Dharma duel okay this is both kinds of
Dharma jewel what's the first one the
book what's the second one
it's the idea behind that smile okay
there's an idea like six inches behind
that smile in here okay and that's the
real Dharma jewel okay so this is
picture is supposed to show the two
kinds of dharma jewel okay and when you
do that meditation you can think about
the two kinds of dharma jewel okay like
all how many dharma jewels do i have in
my life I have Lamia
I have Camilla humor FDC level-1 level-2
normally okay you can count the physical
Dharma jewels you have okay and then you
have to count the mental ones you have
mainly three Lum so num some three
principal pass the word passing Buddhism
means idea it doesn't mean the road okay
three pins what what are three tensile
tests first one yeah I just see life is
trouble life is trouble okay if you
don't do anything you will get old and
stuff its life
okay life is a problem you should feel
sad about it okay if you think things
are going well just wait a while
[Music]
wait until you have to go to doctors
every day you know like the body falls
apart okay
I was reading a Princeton magazine about
ah they're trying to cure old age but
what they figured out was they can't
Kirra old age by carrying separate
diseases like you can't cure diabetes
and then cure cancer and then cure heart
attacks it doesn't matter because what
they found out is a person who gets a
person who died from diabetes is going
to die in three months from heart attack
anyway you see if you cure the diabetes
they would die from heart attack in a
few months if you occur the heart attack
they will die from cancer a few months
after them because the body all falls
apart at the same time that's why they
got diabetes you see I mean you have to
change the cells or you have to take the
karma okay but the first principle path
is just be aware how messed up things
are okay just be aware it's not things
are not going well in this realm okay
people are killing each other people who
are getting old and they're going to die
anyway are killing other people are
going to get old and die anyway why why
spend the time you know have to do
something else for a while
because you're both going to die in your
sin why bother to kill somebody okay
just that's the world it's messed up
okay the world's messed up right now
okay we're this realm there's other
realms that are not messed up we're just
in a bad neighborhood okay all right
second principle power yeah buddy Jenna
I would like to do something to help
everybody okay very basic I would like
to change myself to help everybody else
okay third one
yeah understand it understand the pen
that's all those those three ideas are
Buddhism those two ideas are Dharma
jewel the real Dharma jewel okay the
world's messed up I would like to do
something to help in and understanding
the two husband's is how we can get
there okay
no more fighting okay I about Diamond
Mountain all over the world
I say Dyna Menten is one place where
people will say somebody calls them
stupid they go like this no you like
that's the sign of real practice at
Diamond Mountain you know I call it half
finished sentences you know that's a
sign that Dharma is going on at Diamond
Mountain there are more half any
sentences here than any place else I
ever saw
people are like milli okay